A Guide to the Francis X. (Frank) Sutton papers FA1141
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Ford Foundation, 1936-2012; 2; 24.02 Cubic Feet 51 legal document boxes
  - Ford Foundation History Project, 1953-2010; 1
    - Part II - Nation Building, 1960-2004 (Box 76, Folder 671-673)
    - Part III - Years of Power and Expansion, 1953-2005 (Box 76, Folder 674-677, Box 77, Folder 678-681)
    - Part III - Education, 1964-1967 (Box 77, Folder 682)
    - Part III - Heald Era, 1957-1961 (Box 77, Folder 683)
    - Part III - Population, 1963-1999 (Box 77, Folder 684)
    - Part IV, 2004-2008 (Box 77, Folder 685, Box 78, Folder 686-687)
    - Miscellaneous Binder, 1967-1978 (Box 78, Folder 688)
    - Miscellaneous Binder, 1968-1971 (Box 78, Folder 689-690)
    - Miscellaneous Binder, 1972-1975 (Box 78, Folder 691-692)
    - Miscellaneous Binder, 1978-1979 (Box 79, Folder 693)
    - Miscellaneous Binder, 1988-2007 (Box 79, Folder 694-695)
    - Miscellaneous Binder, 1996-1999 (Box 79, Folder 696-697)
    - Miscellaneous Binder, 1951-1999 (Box 80, Folder 698-700)
- Rockefeller Foundation, 1975-1997; 3; 3.77 Cubic Feet 8 legal document boxes
  - Correspondence, 1989-1992 (Box 80, Folder 701-702)
  - Inter-Office Memos and Meetings, 1985-1988 (Box 80, Folder 703)
  - Report to the Trustees: Conquest of Hunger Program, 1982 September 13 (Box 81, Folder 704)
  - Report to the Trustees: Health Program, 1982 (Box 81, Folder 705)
  - Report to the Trustees: Population Program, Population Sciences Division, 1982 April 7 (Box 81, Folder 706)
  - Report to the Trustees: Redesign of the International Relations Program, 1981 November 19 (Box 81, Folder 707)
  - Reports - Cecilia Loste, 1985 (Box 81, Folder 708)
  - Field Staff Experience Report, 1985 April 15 (Box 81, Folder 709)
  - Consultancy Papers, 1987 (Box 81, Folder 710)
    "Roles for the RF on the Development Process and Its International Setting" and "The Rockefeller Foundation and Africa."
  - Development Paper - Drafts, Outlines, Notes, 1987 (Box 81, Folder 711)
  - General Papers, 1987-1988 (Box 81, Folder 712)
    Includes Rockefeller Foundation 75th Anniversary paper.
  - Foundations and Higher Education - Notes, Drafts, and Talks, 1987 (Box 81, Folder 713)
  - National Center on Adult Literacy (NCAL) Talks, 1991-1992 (Box 82, Folder 714-715)
  - Africa, 1988 (Box 82, Folder 716)
  - CUNY Education, 1971-1987 (Box 82, Folder 717)
  - IBRD, 1987 (Box 82, Folder 718)
  - International Endowments, 1992-1996 (Box 82, Folder 719)
  - Pendelton Herring (Box 82, Folder 720)
  - Kenneth Prewitt, 1985 (Box 82, Folder 721)
  - Science and Technology, 1987-2006 (Box 82, Folder 722)
  - Gemelli Conference, 1992 (Box 82, Folder 723)
  - Bell Colloquium on Development and Planning - Agenda, 1987 (Box 83, Folder 724)
  - Bell Colloquium on Development and Planning - Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 83, Folder 725-727)
  - Bell Colloquium on Development and Planning - Daedalus Paper, 1988 (Box 83, Folder 728)
  - Columbia Seminar on Philanthropy, 1987-1989 (Box 83, Folder 729-730, Box 84, Folder 731)
  - Center for the Study of Philanthropy, 1988-1993 (Box 84, Folder 732)
  - Center for the Study of Philanthropy Working Papers, "Foundations and Higher Education at Home and Abroad", 1986 (Box 84, Folder 733)
  - Graylyn Colloquium, Center for Effective Philanthropy, 1987 (Box 84, Folder 734)
  - WHO/RF Consultation on Promotion of Collaboration between Developing Countries in Research Capabilities Strengthening - Mexico City, 1990 March (Box 84, Folder 735-736)
  - "The American Research University" Daedalus, 1993-1995 (Box 84, Folder 737)
  - "The World in the 1990s" Paper and Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 85, Folder 738)
  - "Technical Change, Development, and Rockefeller Foundation Programs", 1987 (Box 85, Folder 739)
  - Survey of US Institutions Engaged in International Relations Research and Related Activities, 1981 December 1 (Box 85, Folder 740)
  - Bellagio, 1975-1997; 1
    - Family Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 85, Folder 741)
    - General Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 85, Folder 742)
    - Personal Correspondence, 1990-1992 (Box 85, Folder 743-744)
    - Diary Report, 1991 (Box 86, Folder 745)
    - General, 1990-1992 (Box 86, Folder 756-747)
    - History, 1990-1991 (Box 86, Folder 748-749)
    - History - Francesca Weinmann, undated (Box 86, Folder 750)
    - ICIPE Foundation Conference, Bellagio, 1988 March (Box 86, Folder 751)
    - ICIPE Foundation Conference, Bellagio - Background Materials, 1975-1983 (Box 86, Folder 752)
    - Jacqueline Sutton, 1990-1991 (Box 87, Folder 753)
    - Library, 1991-1992 (Box 87, Folder 754)
    - Library Report, 1991 (Box 87, Folder 755)
    - Memorandum, 1990 (Box 87, Folder 756)
    - Report, 1991-1997 (Box 87, Folder 757)
    - Travel, 1991-1992 (Box 87, Folder 758-759)
    - Writings, 1989-1991 (Box 87, Folder 760)
- Social Science Research Council (SSRC), 1922-2009; 4; 2.35 Cubic Feet 5 legal document boxes
  - African Studies, 1983-1984 (Box 88, Folder 761)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1986 (Box 88, Folder 762)
  - Area Committee Task Force, 1986-1989 (Box 88, Folder 763)
  - Beardsley Ruml and the Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial, 1922-1929 (Box 88, Folder 764)
  - Brazil Study, Silvia Raw, 1990 (Box 88, Folder 765)
  - "Building Competences for Policy Analysis and Management in Developing Countries," World Bank paper, 1987-1989 (Box 88, Folder 766)
  - Business, 1985 (Box 88, Folder 767)
  - Clippings, 2000-2009 (Box 88, Folder 768)
  - Correspondence and Notes, 1985-1989 (Box 88, Folder 769-770)
  - Council on Foreign Relations (CFR), 1967-1973 (Box 89, Folder 771)
  - "Education and the Making of Modern Nations," Lake Arrowhead, 1962 (Box 89, Folder 772)
  - Frederic Wakeman Century Nomination, 1988 (Box 89, Folder 773)
  - Frederic Wakeman Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 89, Folder 774)
  - General, 1986-1987 (Box 89, Folder 775)
  - International Research and Training Workshop, New York City, 1993 (Box 89, Folder 776)
  - Items - SSRC Newsletter, 1995-1997 (Box 89, Folder 777)
    Two newsletters: "Kenneth Prewitt Named President of SSRC" and "50 Years of Items Articles, 1947-1997 (Volumes 1-51)"
  - Japan, 1986-1989 (Box 89, Folder 778)
  - Japan Paper, 1989 (Box 90, Folder 779-780)
  - Pendleton Herring, 1965-2005 (Box 90, Folder 781)
  - Personal and By-Laws, 1985-1992 (Box 90, Folder 782)
  - Personnel, 1970-1981 (Box 90, Folder 783)
    Restricted from research - contains salary information.
  - Presidency Search Committee, 1988-1989 (Box 90, Folder 784)
  - Princeton: Institute for Advanced Studies Conference on Fundamental Work and Problem Solving in Public Policy Area, 1970 (Box 90, Folder 785)
  - Proposal for the Support of the Joint Area Committees of the American Council on Learned Societies and the SSRC, 1982 May (Box 90, Folder 786)
  - Sailer Project, 1976-1986 (Box 91, Folder 787)
  - Science Articles, 1985-1986 (Box 91, Folder 788)
  - Science Policy Task Force, Washington D.C., 1985 September (Box 91, Folder 789)
  - Soviet Studies, 2000-2006 (Box 91, Folder 790)
  - SSRC/ACLS, 1985-1998 (Box 91, Folder 791)
  - SSRC/ACLS Advisory Committee on International Programs, 1981-1987 (Box 91, Folder 792-793)
  - SSRC/ACLS International Research Program, National Endowment for the Humanities, 1986 (Box 91, Folder 794)
  - SSRC/ACLS Joint Area Committees Speech - "Rationality, Development and Scholarship", 1982 October 29 (Box 92, Folder 795)
  - SSRC/ACLS Joint Committee on Japanese Studies (JACIP), 1989-1991 (Box 92, Folder 796-797)
  - Verba Committee, 1984 (Box 92, Folder 798)
  - William and Flora Hewlett Foundation, 1983 (Box 92, Folder 799)
- American Foundation for Intellectual Cooperation with Europe (AFICE), 1983-1995; 5; 1.88 Cubic Feet 4 legal document boxes
  - Application and By-laws, 1987 (Box 92, Folder 800)
  - Basic Documents, 1985-1987 (Box 92, Folder 801)
  - Board Correspondence and Minutes, 1987-1991 (Box 92, Folder 802)
  - Bradley Grant, 1988-1992 (Box 93, Folder 803)
  - Budapest, 1989 (Box 93, Folder 804)
  - Correspondence, 1983-1988 (Box 93, Folder 805-808)
  - Correspondence, 1989-1995 (Box 94, Folder 809-811)
  - General, 1988-1992 (Box 94, Folder 812)
  - Krakow, Poland, 1991 (Box 94, Folder 813)
  - Michalski Grant, 1982-1991 (Box 94, Folder 814)
  - Final Meeting, 1993 (Box 94, Folder 815)
  - Tax Returns, 1991-1993 (Box 95, Folder 816-817)
    Restricted from research - contains financial information.
  - Termination, 1991-1993 (Box 95, Folder 818)
  - Working File, 1987 (Box 95, Folder 819)
- Personal Files, 1948-2010; 6; 12.13 Cubic Feet 17 letter document boxes, 3 record storage boxes, and 1 fat file folder
  - Bibliography, 1985-1995 (Box 95, Folder 820-821)
  - Bibliography, 2004-2006 (Box 96, Folder 822)
  - Bibliography and Copies of Writings, 1999-2003 (Box 96, Folder 823)
  - Book Reviews, 1962-1973 (Box 96, Folder 824-825)
  - Correspondence, 1960-2010; 1
    - General Correspondence, 1966-1969 (Box 96, Folder 826-828)
    - General Correspondence, 1966-1983 (Box 97, Folder 829)
    - General Correspondence, 1970-1983 (Box 97, Folder 830-836, Box 98, Folder 837-838)
    - General Correspondence, 1984 (Box 98, Folder 839-842)
    - General Correspondence, 1985 (Box 99, Folder 843-849)
    - General Correspondence, 1986 (Box 100, Folder 850)
    - General Correspondence, 1992 (Box 100, Folder 851)
    - General Correspondence, 1992-1999 (Box 100, Folder 852)
    - General Correspondence, 1993-1996 (Box 100, Folder 853-856)
    - General Correspondence, 1997-2000 (Box 101, Folder 857-862)
    - General Correspondence, 2000-2002 (Box 102, Folder 863-864)
    - General Correspondence, 2000-2009 (Box 102, Folder 865)
    - General Correspondence, 2001-2004 (Box 102, Folder 866-867)
    - General Correspondence, 2002 (Box 102, Folder 868-870)
    - General Correspondence, 2003-2006 (Box 103, Folder 871-875)
    - General Correspondence, 2007-2010 (Box 104, Folder 876-879)
    - Kenya Years Correspondence, 1963-1967 (Box 104, Folder 880-882)
    - Personal Correspondence, 1966-1983
    - Personal Correspondence, 1968-1972 (Box 105, Folder 884-887)
    - Personal Correspondence, 1972-1983 (Box 105, Folder 888, Box 106, Folder 889-891)
      Folder 891 is restricted from research - contains personal information.
    - Personal Correspondence, 1981 (Box 106, Folder 892)
    - Personal Correspondence, 1988 (Box 106, Folder 893)
    - Personal Correspondence, 2004-2005 (Box 106, Folder 894)
    - Professional Correspondence, 1960-1962 (Box 106, Folder 895)
    - Publications Correspondence, 1962-1968 (Box 107, Folder 896-897)
    - Retirement Correspondence, 1983 (Box 107, Folder 898)
  - Curricula Vitae and Appointments, 1968 (Box 107, Folder 899-899A)
    Appointment of Francis Sutton as the deputy vice president of the International Division, Overseas Development Committee, and materials concerning his wife, Jaqueline Sutton.
    Folder 899A is restricted from research - contains personal information.
  - Dateboooks, 1955-2010 (Box 112)
    62 datebooks.
  - Digital Copies of Writings, 1983-1996 (Box 107, Folder 900)
    - Ford Foundation History - Part 1, Nation Building II.2.2., Tables, Population, Philanthropy, Cultural Activities, 2013:053:003
    - Ford Foundation History - Overseas Development & Overseas Development to 1966, Africa & Latin America, Middle East & Africa, Nepal, Turkey, 2013:053:004
    - 1455A, 1509A, 1960A, 1512A, 1456A, FF History Bibliography, Task Force on Science Policy, Philanthropy in Education and Cultural Exchange in China, Aga Khan Report, 2013:053:005
  - Fellowship Awards, 1959 (Box 107, Folder 901)
    Fellowship awards for the American Association for the Advancement of Science and the American Sociological Association.
  - Insurance, 1988-1989 (Box 107, Folder 902)
    Restricted from research - contains personal information.
  - Library Books, undated (Box 107, Folder 903)
    - 8 Books, 2013:053:007 (Box 107, Item 2013:053:007)
  - Marion J. Levy, Jr., 1953-1954 (Box 107, Folder 904)
  - Notebooks, 1950-1989 (Box 113, Box 114)
    126 notebooks. Subjects covered: ADDIS – UNESCO, Africa, Asia, Bangkok, Bangladesh, Bellagio, Berlin, Botswana, Brazil, Bundy on the Middle East, Cameroon, Capetown visit, Chicago Federalism Conference, China, Congo, East Africa, economics, Ethiopia, Europe, Ford Foundation, French Africa, Ghana, Guatemala, India, International Committee, Ivory Coast, Japan, Kenya, Lebanon, Leopolville, Malaysia, Mexico, meeting notes, Middle East, MIT Evian meeting, Morocco, Nairobi Science Center, Nigeria Federalism Conference, Ottowa Education Meeting, Pakistan, Paris, Philippines, Poland, population, refugees, Rhodesia, rural development, Russia, Saudi Arabia, Science, Senegol, Singapore, Smithsonian Symposium, Sudan, Tanganyika, Tunis, UCLA, Uganda, University of Lagos, Vietnam, West Africa, Zambia.
  - Reprints and Articles, 1948-1975 (Box 108, Folder 905-908)
  - General Papers, 1956-1966 (Box 108, Folder 909-910, Box 109, Folder 911-912)
  - Reviews, 1950-1955 (Box 109, Folder 913)
  - Old Writings, 1950-1955 (Box 109, Folder 914-917)
  - Old Writings - Francis and Jacqueline, 1956-1957 (Box 110, Folder 918)
  - Recent Writings, 1995-2005 (Box 110, Folder 919)
  - Publications and Reports, 1970-1989 (Box 110, Folder 920-921, Box 111, Folder 922-925)
  - Speeches and Lectures, 1960-1965 (Box 111, Folder 926)
  - World Map, undated (Box 111, Folder 927)
    - The Routes of My Jet Carpet, 2013:053:006 (Folder 1)